Teaching Resume

Summary

Experienced college professor of mathematics, high school mathematics teacher, and private tutor, with combined 16 years of teaching and tutoring. Seeking evening adjunct teaching (in person), remote and/or On-Line, or evening tutoring position. Experienced in writing curriculum, learning assessment, PowerPoint lectures, interactive lessons, Blackboard, Canvas, PowerSchool, and PowerTeacher. Highly experienced in maintaining instructional websites and interactive white boards.

Education

- Sep. 2017 June 2022: Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Mathematics, Temple University, Philadelphia, PA
- Sep. 2012 June 2016: Master of Arts (M.A.) in Mathematics, Rowan University, Glassboro, N.J.
- Sep. 2008 Sep. 2009: Teacher of Mathematics Certificate, New Jersey Department of Education, Trenton, NJ
- Sep. 2003 June 2007: Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Electrical & Computer Engineering, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ
- Sep. 1999 June 2003: High School Diploma, Pitman High School, Pitman, NJ

Experience

Sep. 2017 – June 2022: Teaching Assistant, Temple University

- Graded assessments and graded coordinated course examinations
- Provided one-on-one tutoring to undergraduate students
- Designed assessments which included midterm examinations and quizzes
- Setup course websites using Blackboard and Canvas
- Designed course syllabi
- Attended coordinated course meetings and provided feedback
- Collaborated with professors to improve and implement effective instructional practices
- Piloted graduate student teaching experiential learning
- Proctored exams
- Provided students mentoring through graduate mathematical talks, SIAM talks/events, mentoring on math department graduate projects, and undergraduate math club talks

Spring 2017: Adjunct Professor, Rowan University

- Adjunct Professor of instruction for evening Calculus I course
- Designed lectures, lecture notes, and interactive lessons

- Designed assessments which include examinations, quizzes, and daily assessments
- Provided abundant office hours before and after class
- Provided ample review sessions for examinations
- Provided frequent feedback to students via email communications and communications through Canvas
- Graded examinations, quizzes, and daily assessments
- Provided feedback on hand graded homework assignments
- Maintained and updated Canvas website on a daily basis
- Utilized announcement features on Canvas to send course updates

Sep. 2009 – June 2017: High School Mathematics Teacher, Clearview Regional School District

- Certified mathematics teacher for 9th-12th grade
- Designed lessons to be interactive and student oriented
- Designed and implemented NJ Core Content Standards
- Attended district professional development events including NJEA teacher conventions
- Attended workshops on implementing "Accountable Talk" in the classroom
- Attended workshops on incorporating technology into the classroom (TI-84 calculators, Geometer's Sketchpad)
- Collaborated with colleagues to design coordinated examinations
- Provided night school instruction and home schooling
- Co-taught courses with special education teachers to meet student needs
- Fulfilled IEP requirements and 504 plans
- Designed lessons to accommodate IEPs and 504 plans
- Provided after school hours for tutoring and extra help
- Participated in extracurricular activities: Mr. Clearview, track/field timer, dance chaperoning, event security
- Communicated actively with parents via phone, email, and website
- Completed required duties: hall monitor, cafeteria monitor, ISS teacher, NJ standardized test proctor
- Participated in student recognition through NHS awards, recommendations, and student-of-themonth selections
- Mentored Rowan University education majors by providing feedback, observations, and experiential learning

Sep. 2011 – June 2016: Private Tutor, Gloucester County, NJ

- Provided one-on-one tutoring and instruction to local county students
- Coordinated scheduling with parents
- Provided hands-on lessons and practice
- Discussed with parents their child's progress
- Used manipulatives to teach grade school through high school topics
- Provided mentoring on goals and career outlook

Teaching

At Temple University

- Spring 2022: Math 1033, Math 1034
- Fall 2021: Math 1039, Math 0702
- Spring 2021: Math 1041
- Fall 2020: Math 1021
- Spring 2020: Math 1041
- Fall 2019: Math 1041
- Summer 2019: Math 1041
- Fall 2018: Math 1039
- Summer 2018: Math 1041
- Spring 2018: Math 0824 (Grader)
- Fall 2017: Math 0824 (Grader)

At Rowan University

- Spring 2017: Calculus I
- Fall 2016: Calculus I

At Clearview Regional High School

- Honors and Advanced Algebra 1
- Honors, Advanced, and Basic Geometry
- $\bullet\,$ Honors Algebra 2
- Honors Calculus I
- College Mathematics

Skills

- Microsoft Office: Word, PowerPoint, Excel
- LaTeX: Syllabi, Lecture Notes, Beamer Presentations
- Geometer's Sketchpad, TI-84 Calculator
- Websites: Canvas, Blackboard
- Student tracking: PowerSchool, PowerTeacher
- Communication: Email, phone, in-person, group meetings
- Lesson Design: Interactive, adaptable, curriculum/assessment
- Interactive white boards

Awards

- March 2022: Dissertation Completion Grant
- May 2022: Jay Novik Graduate Student Fellowship
- Jan. 2019: Temple University Math Department Excellence in Teaching
- Nov. 2018: Certificate of Recognition from SIAM
- 2015–2016: Rowan University Certificate of Achievement in Mathematics
- 2014–2015: Rowan University Certificate of Achievement in Mathematics

Professional Affiliations

- Sep. 2018 June 2022: Temple University SIAM Chapter President and Member
- Sep. 2018 June 2022: SIAM Member and journal subscriber
- Sep. 2017 June 2022: AMS Member
- Sep. 2017 June 2022: MAA Member
- Sep. 2015 June 2017: Pi Mu Epsilon Chapter Member, Rowan University
- Sep. 2008 June 2017: NJEA Member, Clearview Education Association
- Sep. 2006 Sep. 2008: IEEE Member and journal subscriber

Languages

- English: Native Language
- Spanish: Conversational and Written

Hobbies

• Reading: Neuroscience, mathematics, scifi, history, poetry

• Writing: Mathematical articles, poetry, drawing, painting

• Personal Fitness: Running, lifting, hiking

• Sports: Orioles/Phillies (baseball), Ravens/Eagles (football)

• Games: Video and board games

• Travel: US and international

• Dining: Restaurant hopping